Emily B. Siegel

Data Scientist and Geoscientist with 9+ years of achieving actionable insights with diverse datasets. Passion for problem-solving and a reputation for mastering new roles and technologies, as well as communicating complex information to nontechnical audiences.

PROJECTS

- Automating Securities Identifier (CUSIP) Assignments through ETL & ML
- Starbucks Customer Segmentation using K-Means Clustering
- Breast Cancer Detection in Mammograms using Convolutional Neural Networks
- Classifying Passive vs. Active Revenge in Related Subreddits using NLP
- Predicting Ames, Iowa Real Estate Prices with Linear Regression

EXPERIENCE

S&P Global Ratings, Centennial, CO — Data Scientist

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

- Develop Python automation solutions incl. ML models that maximize data capabilities for stakeholders throughout the whole project lifecycle, from design and development through testing and deployment.
- Accomplished over \$300K in hours saved for projects completed in 2022.

Well Data Labs, Denver, CO — *Data Research Analyst & Support Analyst* FEB 2019 - MAY 2021

- Applied best practices in statistical analysis to drive business value.
- Validated, tested, and monitored the performance of machine learning models. Standardized accuracy metrics and optimized testing workflow.
- Automated high-frequency time series data wrangling and analyses using Excel VBA and Python. Integrated Python scripts in custom built dashboards.
- Coauthored a peer-reviewed paper, client case studies, and blog posts that address key market needs while proposing data-driven solutions and strategies.
- Tracked product usage, deployed customer retention initiatives, and developed technical documentation with every new release.

Reliance OFS (formerly FMC Technologies), Denver, CO — Log Data Analyst

AUG 2015 - FEB 2019

- Due to newly acquired technology and previous pulsed neutron expertise, I implemented a new data service, increasing revenue and bringing in 3 new clients.
- Assessed wellbore integrity and identified potential casing and cement issues to maximize the efficiency of field operations while ensuring safety.
- Trained 2 new analysts on all department functions and created instructional documentation including technical manuals, reference materials, and workflows.

Baker Hughes, Denver, CO — Geoscientist / Team Lead

APRIL 2013 - AUG 2015

- Led the Cased Hole Petrophysics team of 5 people within the Reservoir Development group. Resulted in 600+ successfully delivered projects yearly.
- Processed and analyzed data using various petrophysical techniques and technologies to provide and present solutions to clients.
- Vital internal role mentoring and teaching data processing techniques, expanding the company's Cased Hole business internationally to South American markets.

(720) 355-3708
emilybsiegel@gmail.com
LinkedIn
GitHub
Data Science Portfolio

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Data Science Immersive
JUNE 2021- SEPT 2021

University of Vermont

B.S. Geology, Minor Studio Art AUG 2008 - MAY 2012

SKILLS

Core Competencies:

Analytics + Research Machine Learning Cognitive Automation Project Management Technical Writing Presenting Lean-Agile

Software:

PyCharm | Jupyter |
Databricks | Alteryx | Data
visualization (Spotfire &
PowerBI) | CRM (Salesforce)
| Version control (GitHub,
Azure DevOps & BitBucket) |
Software product planning
(Pivotal Tracker) | Product
UX (Pendo) | Adobe Creative

LANGUAGES

Python | SQL | Excel VBA | Bash | Hebrew | French

PUBLICATIONS

SPE 204145 (2021)
Employing a Suite of
Machine-Learning
Algorithms in a Holistic
Approach to Trouble-Stage
Recognition and Failure
Diagnostics